export const data = {
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What does JSX stand for in ReactJS?",
        "options": [
          "JavaScript XML",
          "Java Syntax Extension",
          "XML Script",
          "JS Extension"
        ],
        "correctOption": "JavaScript XML"
      },
      {
        "question": "In React, what is the purpose of state?",
        "options": [
          "To store and manage data that can change over time",
          "To declare static variables",
          "To define the structure of components",
          "To handle routing in a React application"
        ],
        "correctOption": "To store and manage data that can change over time"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the significance of the 'render' method in a React component?",
        "options": [
          "It defines the initial state of the component",
          "It is responsible for rendering the component's UI",
          "It handles asynchronous operations",
          "It is used for defining PropTypes"
        ],
        "correctOption": "It is responsible for rendering the component's UI"
      },
      {
        "question": "How can you pass data from a parent component to a child component in React?",
        "options": [
          "Using props",
          "Using state",
          "Using context",
          "Using refs"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Using props"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'componentDidMount' lifecycle method in React?",
        "options": [
          "To update the component's state",
          "To perform actions after the component has mounted",
          "To handle component unmounting",
          "To define component propTypes"
        ],
        "correctOption": "To perform actions after the component has mounted"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which hook is used for performing side effects in a functional component?",
        "options": [
          "useEffect",
          "useCallback",
          "useState",
          "useReducer"
        ],
        "correctOption": "useEffect"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is React Router used for?",
        "options": [
          "To manage state in a React application",
          "To handle HTTP requests",
          "To create navigation in a React application",
          "To define Redux actions"
        ],
        "correctOption": "To create navigation in a React application"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'key' prop in React when rendering lists of elements?",
        "options": [
          "To specify the order of elements in the list",
          "To provide a unique identifier for each list item",
          "To define the style for list items",
          "To control the visibility of list items"
        ],
        "correctOption": "To provide a unique identifier for each list item"
      },
      {
        "question": "In React, what is a controlled component?",
        "options": [
          "A component that is directly manipulated by the DOM",
          "A component that manages its own state internally",
          "A component that receives data through props and notifies changes via callbacks",
          "A component that uses Redux for state management"
        ],
        "correctOption": "A component that receives data through props and notifies changes via callbacks"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the purpose of React Fragments?",
        "options": [
          "To create reusable components",
          "To group multiple elements without adding extra nodes to the DOM",
          "To define global styles for a React application",
          "To handle form submissions in React"
        ],
        "correctOption": "To group multiple elements without adding extra nodes to the DOM"
      }
    ]
  }
  